Johnson, Cyril Woolen Company Records 6589
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cyril Johnson Woolen Company Records
1919-1963
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
6589
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Correspondence, records (documents), scrapbooks.
Collection contains incoming correspondence, 1930-1963, reports on cloth production for the armed forces, 1941-1945, and other war-related materials; papers concerning the mill closing, 1962-1963; and information files including clippings, pamphlets, notes and articles on wages and hours, company history, fashions, mill closings, and imports.
11035378
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
J. Riggs, September 11, 2019
EAD encoding:
Marcie Farwell, October 09, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The company was founded in 1879 and was located in Stafford Springs, Connecticut, with selling offices on Madison Avenue in New York. It manufactured fine wool suitings and overcoatings. The company was sold in 1963 to the Stevens Companies. During the period covered in this collection, it operated 10 sets of cards, 100 looms, and 4,000 spindles. In 2014, The American Woolen Company bought the Cyril Johnson and Warren Mills in Stafford Springs, CT to produce their American made textiles.
Scope and Contents
Collection contains incoming correspondence, 1930-1963, on topics such as machinery, advertising, fashion, business conditions, imports and mill closings. It also contains cloth test results compared with Japanese cloth for tensile strength and shrinkage, including consulting report from Barnes Textile Associates; survey of carding machinery with recommendations from Davis & Furber Machine Co.; reports on cloth production for the armed forces, 1941-1945, and other war- related materials; papers concerning the mill closing, 1962-1963; and information files including clippings, pamphlets, notes and articles on wages and hours, company history, fashions, mill closings, and imports.
Custodial History
American Textile History Museum Collection, gift of the Cyril Johnson Woolen Company.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6589 F: Cyril Johnson Woolen Company Films 6589 G: Cyril Johnson Woolen Company Graphics 6589 P: Cyril Johnson Woolen Company Photographs
Advertising; Coats; Men's clothing industry; Selling; Suits (Clothing); Swatches (Dry-goods); Textile industry; Wool fabrics; Woolen and worsted manufacture; Wool industry; Samples (Cloth); Stafford Springs (Conn.); United States; Cyril Johnson Woolen Company
11035378
- Correspondence - Machinery, 1952-1961; Text (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  September 29, 1952-September 12, 1961
- Correspondence - C.D. Newell, 1933-1938; Text (Box 1, Folder 2)
  New York office to mill in Connecticut; February 1933 - August 1938
- Correspondence - C.D. Newell, 1938-1943; Text (Box 1, Folder 3)
  New York office to mill in Connecticut; November 1938 - October 1941, October 1943
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1924-1963; Text (Box 1, Folder 4)
  June 1924, June 1935 - July 1963
- Correspondence - Incoming Miscellaneous, 1924-1963; Text (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Imports - Correspondence, 1953-1960; Text (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Mill closings; April 1953 - April 1960
- Correspondence - To F.C. Luce from Wool Institute, 1930; Text (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Cloth production for Armed Forces, 1941-1945; Text (Box 1, Folder 8)
  circa 1941-1945
- Cloth Test Results, 1945-1960; Text (Box 1, Folder 9)
  1945, 1957-1960
- Survey of Carding Machinery, 1958; Text (Box 1, Folder 10)
  and Recommendations by Davis & Furber Machine Company; July 11, 1958
- Army-Navy "E" Award, 1943; Text (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Company Bulletin Re: Suggestion Box, Text (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Undated
- Guilford Re: Purchase of C.J.W. Company, 1962; Text (Box 1, Folder 13)
  August 10, 1962
- News Release - C. Johnson Mill Closing, 1963; Text (Box 1, Folder 14)
  April 26, 1963
- Wage Scales and Hours Report, 1919-1923; Text (Box 2, Folder 1)
  1919, 1923
- New Clippings - Re: Purchase of C.J.W. Company, 1962; Text (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Purchase by Guilford Industries; July 1962
- News Clippings - Re: C.J. Woolen Company, 1950-1959; Text (Box 2, Folder 3)
- News Clippings - Re: Army-Navy "E" Award, 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newspaper - "Daily News Record", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 5)
  March 29, 1943
- Newspaper - "Daily News Record", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 6)
  August 12, 1943
- Newspaper - "Daily News Record", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 7)
  August 17, 1943
- Newspaper - "Daily News Record", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 8)
  August 18, 1943
- Newspaper - "The Stafford Press", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 9)
  July 15, 1943
- Newspaper - "The Stafford Press", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 10)
  August 5, 1943
- Newspaper - "The Stafford Press", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newspaper - "The Stafford Press", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 12)
  August 19, 1943
- Newspaper - "The Stafford Press", 1945; Text (Box 2, Folder 13)
  February 1, 1945
- Newspaper Page - "The Springfield Sunday Union and Republican", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 14)
  July 18, 1943
- Newspaper Page - "The Hartford Times", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 15)
  April 23, 1943
- Newspaper Page - "The Hartford Times", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Newspaper - "The Rockville Journal", 1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 17)
- News Clippings - Re: Mill Strike, Vacation, Town History, 1935-1943; Text (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Strike - 1935, Vacation - 1943, Town history - 1943
- Synthetics, 1952; Text (Box 2, Folder 19)
- News Clippings - Memos Attached, 1958-1959; Text (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Re: Wool industry, general fashion trends
- Imports - Script Tables Listing Import, 1954-1961; Text (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Imports/Mill Closings, 1953-1963; Text (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Printed on typescript material
- Newspaper Ads & Articles - Re: Imports & Mill Closings, 1954-1957; Text (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Basic Troubles with the Sheep, Wool, Woolen and Worsted Textiles, and Lamb Slaughtering Industries", 1961; Text (Box 2, Folder 24)
  By Laurence T. Ritchie; February 5, 1961
- "Camel-Hair Fabrics", Text (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Carbon copy; No author; Undated
- Abstract of Birth Record, 1928-1938; Text (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Francis Henry Mitchell; 1928, 1938